In this video, we will be looking at an
example
where we can apply Ohm's law and what
we've
learned over here with Kirchhoff's current
law
to solve a circuit problem.
This problem asks us to find the current
of
all the resistance points, so we need to
find
the current over here, I1, I2, I3, I4,
and I5. So how do we start?
Well, first of all, we have all the
resistors,
we have the total voltage of the thing, so
a
first optimal step would be to calculate
the
total current, because that way we can use
Kirchhoff's
law. So in order to find the total
current,
I current, we would have to have the total
voltage
over the total resistance.
We have the total voltage, it's 132 volts,
so
how do we find the total resistance?
Well, the total resistance could be given
by
our other formula, R total. It's the sum
of
the resistors of this section and this
section,
because if we treat these as a series, we
can
just add them up. But these are in
parallel,
so before we treat it, we kind of have to
combine
it, so it's 1 over 2.4 plus 1 over 1.7,
and
this is the formula that I explained
earlier
about here. This is the total resistance
of
this parallel circuit, and we will do the
same
thing to get the total resistance of this
parallel
circuit, so we can treat them as single
resistors
in a whole series circuit.
1 over 60 plus 1 over 20 plus 1 over 30.
And the reason why we're adding them is
we're
treating this as a single resistor and
this
as another single resistor, so it would be
the
resistance for the whole series. So the
resistance
of the first section when we type this in
our
calculator would be about 1
ohm. 1 ohm plus the resistor in the other
section
when you type it in the calculator would
be
about 10 ohms.
So the total resistance of this circuit, R
total,
would be 11 ohms, equals 11 ohms.
I'll actually write this in yellow to make
sure
that everything I write in yellow will be
calculations.
So R total equals 11 ohms.
So using this formula, since we have R
total
now, I total would be equal to V total 132
over 11, which is 12.
12 amps. So I total equals 12 amps.
Now we need to calculate the individual
currents
here. In order to do that, we can use
Ohm's
law and the chart we've done here. It's
really
handy to know this, and you guys have
probably
learned it before. It was grade 9
curriculum.
So we can use this in order to solve for
each
individual circuit. So I'll go over this
pretty
quickly. We know that the current
everywhere
is the same in a series circuit.
So the current over here will be equal to
amps. The current over here is equal to 12
amps.
So looking at the parallel circuit, the
total
current of the parallel circuit would be
equal
to 12 amps. Not in each branch, the total
current
will be 12 amps. So let's call this branch
X,
and let's call this branch Y. The total
current
of branch X is 12 amps.
The total resistance of branch X, we
calculated
over here, is 1 ohm.
So by doing that, we can calculate the
total
voltage. The total voltage in branch X
would
be equal to the total current times the
total
resistance, which is equal to 12 volts.
So since it's a parallel circuit, over
here
would be 12 volts, over here would be 12
volts.
Now let's do the same thing over here.
We know that we don't actually have to
calculate
it. We could if we want. But we know that
the
total voltage in a series is the sum of
all
the individual voltages. If we know that
the
voltage here at X is 12 ohms, then we know
equals Vx plus Vy.
And if X is 12 ohms, then the voltage at Y
would
be 120 when we calculate it.
120 volts. So since it's parallel, this
would
be 120 volts, 120 volts, and 120 volts.
And now we know that we can easily
calculate
for the resistance, sorry, the current.
So let's start with I1.
I1 is V1, or Vx in this case, because it's
parallel, over R1. So it's 12 over 2.4,
and
you'll get 5 amps. I2 is Vx over R2,
which is 12 over 1.7 ohms, which you'll
get
7 amps about. 7A.
I3 is over here, so now the new voltage is
in all three branches. So Vy over R3, 120
over
60, that would be 2 amps.
Same thing for I4 and I5.
I4 equals Vy over R4, equals 120 over 20,
that would be equal to 6 amps.
And finally, I5 is Vy over R5, which is
over 30, which is 4 amps.
And these would be your currents in all of
the
sections. Now,
you might be wondering how we can use
Kirchhoff's
Law to actually help us in this question.
Well, we've done all of these
calculations,
but we need a way to check.
A question might ask, confirm your answers
using
Kirchhoff's Current Law. Usually, they
would
give you a point where you can use
Kirchhoff's
Law, because Kirchhoff's Law, like we said
before,
only applies to a junction. So, in this
case,
let's say they give you point, I'll do
this
in red, point C over here.
Now, the current will be going this way,
because
positive to negative.
And what we do is we can calculate the
total
current that exits out of this parallel
circuit.
And we can also calculate the total
current
that goes in here, or the total current of
y
and the total current of x. Well, the
total
current of y is essentially just I1 plus
I2.
If you remember the chart we've learned,
in
a parallel, it's a sum. And it's going to
be
positive since it's going inside the
junction,
as we've learned. So, according to
Kirchhoff's
Law, the sum of all the voltages should be
equal
to zero. So, I1 plus I2 plus I3 plus I4
plus I5 equals zero.
The reason why I can just add it is
because
these are in parallel, which means you add
them.
And these are also in parallel, which
means
you add them, and they're going inside the
middle
junction. I1 and I2 would be positive, so
five
plus seven, five plus seven.
And since the current goes outwards over
here,
and now the current's going this way,
these
currents would all be negative because
they're
going away from the junction. They're not
actually
negative, it's just a direction.
Plus negative two, plus negative six, plus
negative
four. And let's do it as a proof, so
left-hand
side, right-hand side is equal to zero.
And five plus seven is twelve, negative
two
minus six minus four is negative twelve.
So, zero. So, it does make sense.
Kirchhoff's Law affirms that our
calculations
make sense because the total voltage at
this
junction is zero. Sorry, the total current
at
this junction is zero. And the total
current
at any junction should be zero if you try
to
calculate it. And that's basically a
really
good use of Kirchhoff's Law. It's used to
make
sure that your calculations are correct,
especially
when you have time during a test, such as
AP
or IB. But IB might be time-heavier, so
unless
it asks you to do it, it's just a good
thing
to know and assure that your answers are
right.
Thank you for watching, and I hope you
learned
how to do these types of circuit problems.
Bye!